BRYANT MACMAHON

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROFILE

Full Stack Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience in Business Management. Problem solving enthusiast and strong communicator with fervor to bring skills, talents and energy to a development team solving innovative and challenging software issues.

SKILLS

Coding Languages

Javascript, Python, CSS, HTML, SQL, Ruby

Frameworks/Technologies

Flask, Node.js, Express, React, Redux, jQuery, Jest, Jasmine, REST APIs, Bootstrap, Chrome Devtools, Bash/Shell, Visual Studio, Bootstrap, Markdown, Git

Key Strengths

Googling, Test Driven Development, Agile

EDUCATION

Springboard Software Engineering Career Track | March 2021 - January 2022

- Mastering skills in front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, data structures and algorithms.
- Weekly 1 on 1 meetings with a senior level, industry expert.
- 700+ hours of course material
- 200+ hours of coding immersion

Indiana University - School of Public and Environmental Affairs | September 2011 - June 2013

- Treasurer, Inter-fraternity Council
- Social Chair, Theta Chi Fraternity

EXPERIENCE

CarbonSight

Springboard Capstone Project

- Application for calculating Carbon Footprint
- Calculations are built from third party API endpoints for flights, electricity & vehicles.
- Technologies: Flask, PostgreSQL, REST APIs, Bootstrap, Axios, wtforms, bcrypt
- Deployment: carbonsight.herokuapp.com

Front End Web Developer

Bird Digital | December 2020 - April 2021

- Designed and deployed static websites for customers from varying industries.
- Managed project from sale to deployment.
- Technologies: Gatsby, Wordpress, Figma

Store Manager

T-Mobile | July 2020 - December 2020

- Oversaw all aspects of the sales floor including scheduling, escalations, inventory, employee training, financial discrepancies and problem solving.
- Consistently exceeded monthly overall sales and specific revenue stream goals.
- Troubleshot extensive carrier and crippling device issues with customers.

CONTACT

Main Cell: 208-908-3163
Work Cell: 503-421-0374
Email: bryantmac@gmail.com
Portfolio: https://zataara.xyz
Location: Portland, OR 97232
LinkedIn: @bryantmac

Github: @zataara

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Specialist

Apple | October 2021 - Present

- Assessed customers' support needs upon arrival, using empathy and intuition to strengthen the customers' relationship with Apple.
- Troubleshot and diagnosed software and hardware issues with iOS devices: Mac, iPhone, iPad, Apple Watch, & accessories.
- Provided personalized training to new users on how to best use and optimize performance of their devices.
- Mentored and assisted team members in providing superior customer service.

Assistant Manager

Brother's Bar & Grill | Dec 2016 - June 2020

- Guided sales initiatives to optimize month over month financial growth.
- Conducted job interviews, evaluated employees skills, and mentored new hires into becoming successful team members.
- Organized schedules, workflows and shift coverage to meet expected demands.
- Maintained inventory accuracy by counting stock-on-hand and reconciling discrepancies.
- Secured revenue, accurately monitoring transactions to eliminate financial issues.

Bartender

Kilroy's Bar & Grill | January 2011 - May 2016

- Worked in an extremely fast paced, high energy and oftentimes chaotic environments.
- Frequently spent 15+ hour days behind the bar for game-days and holidays.

Assistant General Manager

The Park On Morton | August 2013 - January 2015

- Managed all financial aspects for a 500 person property.
- Created, balanced, and tracked annual budget with transparency and accuracy.
- Worked closely with residents to maintain rapport and annual retention.
- Assisted legal counsel on a monthly basis to handle evictions.
- Leased property to 97% in its first year of operations.

Trainer

Panera Bread | August 2010 - April 2011

 Trained new employees to effectively adhere to company standards and procedures.

Camp Counselor

Miracle Camp | May 2008 - August 2008

- Supervised groups of 12-15 boys, ages 5-18, for 9 consecutive weeks of 6-day camps.
- Counseled inner city Chicago youth in social and family issues.

Advertiser

Brent's Cards | January 2007 - May 2008

- Conducted sales of promotional merchandise through eBay and Amazon.
- Created and designed online storefronts on eBay and Amazon.
- Built advertisements for presidential candidate, Mike Huckabee.

.